JASON SOFTWARE

ENGINEER

I jtg2078@gmail.com

\(+886936412322

in jtq2078

೧ jtg2078

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Objective-C

Python

JavaScript

HTML

CSS

C#

FRAMEWORKS

iOS-SDK

AppEngine-Python-SDK

SciPy

Node

React

jQuery

IDES

Xcode

Sublime Text

PyCharm

VERSION CONTROL **SYSTEMS**

GitHub

DATABASES

PostgreSQL

MongoDB

Redis

Google-DataStore

OPERATING SYSTEMS

OSX

Linux

Windows

PROGRAMMING CHALLENGES

Project Euler - 120 solved

Summary

- Full stack web developer familiar with wide range of technologies, experienced in API design, SPA, and scalable backends
- Veteran iOS engineer with more than 10 app in app store, and well versed in iOS technology stack
- Strong track record in delivering software products and services, effective in both freelance, remote or team based environment

Projects

Alfred - Home Security Surveillance IP Camera

role: primary developer

tech: CoreVideo, VideoToolBox, XMPP, RTP, WebRTC, H264, ICE, AudioUnit

impact: integrated various frameworks, components, and solutions to deliver a cloud-based IP camera app which streams h.264 video and audio with minimum bandwidth requirement

Expr

role: primary developer

tech: AppEngine, WebApp2, Jinja, ndb-datastore, memcached, MapReduce, task-queue, iOS app, React.js, Compass, Gulp.js impact: designed and developed the backend, the frontend and the iOS app for Expr.cc, a reddit-clone social discussion platform

LoL Worlds

role: co-developed with my brother

tech: AppEngine, iOS, Angular.js, Node.js, Express.js

impact: designed the backend system for fetching third-party data, and developed an easy to use backend real-time play-by-play data entry system

Find Tea

role: primary developer

tech: AppEngine, iOS, jQuery, web-crawling, BeautifulSoup, LBS

impact: created automated crawlers for many bubble-tea franchise in taiwan, and extracted useful location data from many illformed html web pages

Employment

Alfred Labs Taipei / San Francisco 10 2014 - Current

Software Engineer

- designed and delivered iOS version of Alfred on schedule with targeted spec and features in 6 months
- established rapid design-implement-test process which shorten release cycle from 1 month to 1 week

DoubleX Taipei 09 2012 - 09 2014 Software Engineer

- delivered 55688 app on schedule despite constant spec and requirement changes

- delivered Carrefour iOS app within 3 months and satisfied every client's requests
- completed every client project(6 iOS apps, 3 backend systems and 2 SPA) successfully

Mobile01 Taipei

04 2012 - 08 2012

Software Engineer - completed the first version of company's first IM app on iOS platform on schedule in 3 months

- optimized and rewrote backend system's messages processing throughput by 150%.

Fingertip Creative Tainei Software Engineer 03 2011 - 03 2012

- completed major client project TaiwanFresh app within schedule(7 mo) and received excellent client feedback
- led the dev team to design and engineered the company main e-commerce platform Tiny Square in 6 months

RMS San Francisco 08 2007 - 08 2010 Software Engineer

- completed all the features and improvements successfully for development of RiskLink 8.0/9.0/10.0
- ranked in top 10 percent performers for performance evaluation in 2008 and 2009
- fixed more than 150 bugs and issues and ranked as one of top performers in bug fixing in 2009 and 2010

Education

The State University of New York at Stony Brook B.S. Computer Science 2007

Udacity

Nanodegree Full Stack Web Developer

Nanodegree Data Analyst